Truly, who'd have imagined
that famously obstinate Norman would
take an orphan as an apprentice?
That is a surprise.
He used to be so adamant that he
wouldn't pass on his skills to anyone.
Wh-What is his apprentice's name?
His name is Arthur. He's a twelve
or thirteen-year-old boy.
Yes, of course.
Marie... Don't tell me that you think
Anastasia might still be alive?
You think that Norman's apprentice
might be your sister?
That seems highly unlikely.
Yes, of course.
I understand.
A few weeks have passed since
my father was issued a summons.
Episode 10 "Please Call Off the Betrothal"
There hasn't been any response yet.
All I can do is devote everything I have
to learning aristocratic etiquette...
and write letters of thanks to pass to the
guests who attend the betrothal ceremony.
All so that I can grow the slightest
bit more worthy of Lord Kyros.
Yesterday, I dispatched a carriage
to bring the baron here directly.
I see.
If he still doesn't comply, I may have
to resort to slightly rougher measures.
I'm so sorry.
If my father remains in hiding,
as his blood relative,
I'm prepared to face any punishment.
Please don't say that! Do you
think I would allow such a thing?
But someone has to accept responsibility
for his actions, don't they?
Marie!
I'm all right.
I'll go to my dance practice now.
I have nothing left to teach her.
She works so much harder
than most people.
Yes.
Don't you ever let her go.
I know.
Noble lady,
will you favor me with a dance?
With pleasure... sir.
You really have gotten good at this!
I'm happy to hear you say so.
I've practiced a lot, so—
What's wrong? Are you all right?
I-I'm sorry. My feet suddenly got tangled.
You're pushing yourself far too hard.
Rest a little.
No, I haven't pushed myself at all!
By the betrothal ceremony,
I'll do better than—
Marie!
Are you all right? Shouldn't
you go to your rooms and rest?
No, I'm fine.
No, you're not!
Ever since we heard about Norman's
apprentice, you've been acting strangely!
You're still thinking about
Anastasia, aren't you?
Th-That's not...
There's something bothering you, isn't there?
I saw someone... near the artisans' quarter.
Someone who looked like my sister.
Someone blonde.
All right. Let's meet Norman's apprentice.
What?
Once you've seen him with your own
eyes, your feelings should lighten.
Yes.
I've brought Smith Norman.
Norman, it's been a while, hasn't it?
It has been indeed, Count Granado.
Norman... what happened to your eyes?
Three years ago while I was working,
shards of hot iron sprang
loose and pierced my goggles.
I can still see light and dark and colors,
so I am able to live surprisingly normally.
What about people's faces?
If it's someone I know
well, then I can get by.
But my apprentice waits
on all the new customers.
Speaking of which, where is your apprentice?
Why isn't he here?
My apologies.
I told him to come with me,
but he said he wasn't feeling well.
We'll send another messenger.
Norman, Luiphon said that your
apprentice is a young man,
but how do you know he's a man?
Well, he said so himself. Why do you ask?
You can't mean that you think
I'm sheltering a woman?
Don't even joke about such a thing!
I would never let a woman into my workshop!
And Arthur is still just a fledgling,
but he has both talent and grit!
I-I see. I heard that you met
Arthur in the royal capital.
Yes, he was fleeing from being
sold off to some nobles,
so he was wandering the
town with no money at all.
When I said that I was a
button artisan, he said,
"Really, old man? Then
make me your apprentice!"
What?
He said that himself?
Indeed.
He said, "I'm sick of a life of bein' taken
advantage of by rotten, rich villains!"
Oh my.
Just as I thought. He must be someone else.
A noble's daughter would
never speak that way.
His skills in the craft still need work,
but his grasp of clothing is exceptional.
Clothes for women to dress as men, was it?
He said he'd been making those
sorts of things for a while now.
Clothes for women to dress as
men? Th-That's just like...
What an unusual hobby.
Were his parents artisans, too?
He doesn't seem to want
to talk about his parents.
No matter what I ask, he always answers,
"Quit asking, you moron!
I'm just a raggedy cat!"
Imagine.
What an entertaining apprentice!
Indeed.
Next time, I'll bring some of the
men's clothes for women that he made.
I look forward to it.
They'd likely suit Marie unexpectedly well.
Marie?
Marie!
Where are you?
Please come out!
Begin a search of the immediate area at once!
Yes, miss!
Marie!
Where are you?
Lady Marie!
My lady, why...
Mister Johan! Have you seen our lady?
Confound it!
Why can't I find her?
Marie? Are you here?
You are, aren't you? May I come in?
Stay away.
Why this room?
This room?
Oh, now that he mentions it...
For some reason... I felt like
this place would protect me.
Please... Please let me join you.
It gets cold here. Let's drink some
hot tea and calm ourselves.
Lord Kyros...
Marie...
Hearing Mister Norman made me certain of it.
My sister loved to make clothes.
And those lines from
The Tale of the Raggedy Red Cat.
She is alive, just as I thought.
And now there's no reason for
me to be allowed to stay here.
What do you mean?
Even if Anastasia is alive, our feelings
for each other are shared, aren't they?
My sister is a kind,
beautiful, wonderful woman.
No matter what I do, I'll
never be a match for her.
I know that your feelings
for me aren't a lie.
But... it's only because
you don't know my sister.
If you knew her properly, I'm certain
you'd fall in love with her, too.
More than you could ever love someone like me.
What are you saying?!
It's you I love!
I've loved you all this time!
Are you saying... you can simply
cast aside your feelings for me?
Cast them aside?
I could never cast them aside!
You don't have to worry.
I love you just as you are.
The me that you love is the beautiful me...
not the ugly human that I am.
I... loathe myself.
Marie.
I thought that I wished my sister
were still alive, and yet...
If my sister were dead, then I'd
be able to stay by your side.
I allowed myself to dream.
My true feelings are so repulsive...
I'm certain they would disappoint you.
Now, while you still love me...
Please call off the betrothal.
I will return to the Shaderan household.
All right. I will grant your wish.
Thank you for taking care of me.
I'll dedicate my life to reimbursing you for
my living costs and for ending our betrothal.
You don't have to worry about any of that.
I will drive her home.
Marie... is this really what you want?
Yes.
I'm too weak.
I know that you don't mean
what you say, and yet...
I...
Marie, isn't there anything
left that I can do?
Nothing.
You've already done more than enough for me.
I see.
If I can find the courage...
If I can grow a little
bit stronger as a man...
then one day, I promise I will come to you.
I beg of you, please wait
for me until that day.
I left without saying goodbye to everyone.
Even though they took such good care of me.
If he'd taken someone as
ungrateful as me as his wife,
it would bring misfortune to everyone.
This is the right thing to do after all.
I'm disappointed in the master.
I never imagined he was so weak and cowardly.
Cowardly?
Instead of choosing a happy future for you,
he chose to stop your tears in the present.
Because he's afraid of hurting you.
Afraid of hurting me?
I didn't want to get hurt,
so I hurt him instead,
and he worked to protect me.
I'm certain it's because
I seemed about to break.
Is that weakness?
Eyes more beautiful than any star...
From the first moment I
met you, I've loved you.
I love you, Marie.
I love you from the bottom of my heart.
And no matter what happens,
I will always be by your side.
You are beautiful!
Lord Kyros always told
me exactly how he felt.
And yet I...
All I've done is run away!
The first treasure I've ever found.
I was so afraid of losing it...
that I lied and said I didn't want it.
I didn't want to get hurt,
so I tried to convince myself
that I wasn't worthy.
But... the truth is, I've always wanted it.
I've wanted it so badly
that I couldn't stand it.
Mio, please! The carriage!
Understood.
Wh-What?
We'll be back very soon.
Up until just now, we've simply been
circling near the castle, you see?
What?
The carriage will rock a bit. Please
be careful not to bite your tongue.
I let it slip away once, but this
time everything will be fine!
I won't run anymore!
I won't lie to myself anymore!
Lord Kyros!
The coward... the one who
needs more courage is me!
So, I'm going to tell you properly!
I want you!
And everyone in this castle, too!
Everything related to you, all of it!
I don't want to let anyone else have it!
Please give all of yourself to me!
Lord Kyros?
Why are you behind me?
I was chasing after you.
Stupid! Marie, you're so stupid!
You're not going to leave anymore, right?
You're going to say you're home now, right?
Yes. I'm home, Cillie.
My lady...
Welcome home.
Everyone...
I'm so sorry for worrying you.
The ultimate apple pie!
Just one bite and you'll
never think of leaving again!
You're right.
What do you think the secret ingredient is?
Miss Marie?
Please don't go anywhere.
Kyros always ran away from
falling in love with anyone,
but now he's finally met you.
Yes, I won't run anymore.
It happened before I even realized it.
Here, in this castle, little by
little, I built the real thing...
A place where I belong.
That's right. I...
Marie...
Is he searching for me?
He's sort of... cute.
Pardon the intrusion.
Mio?
If you'd like, the bath is ready.
Tunika has prepared everything.
Y-Yes!
The hot bath was lovely.
I wonder if Lord Kyros is awake yet.
What if he's looking for me again?
Don't move!
Where is Marie Shaderan's room?
That voice...
It's so dark it's hard to see.
Hurry up and show me—
Marie, are you all right?
Lord Kyros?
I woke up, so I came looking
for you. That was too close!
Wh-What'd you think you're
doing, you gargantuan man?
What's this? Quite the
spirited little hoodlum.
I-It's not like that. She's...
my older sister, Anastasia!
Miss Marie is family,
and I'm so glad that she came back!
Wait. Miss Anastasia?
Next time, "The Empty Princess Lives."
Episode 11 "The Empty Princess Lives"
Be sure to watch.